YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 6. Program: Series VII. War Work and Defense Services 324_rg6_s7
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES VII. WAR WORK AND DEFENSE SERVICES
  - Subseries A. World War I
    Other War Work Council Committees coordinated programs to find housing for women workers who had left home to work at camps and in industry, for women agricultural workers, and for matching volunteer workers with jobs. The Committee on Organization and Extension of Regular Work analyzed where special war work could connected with the regular city work. Staff specialists in topics such as Recreation and Pageantry and Drama, helped Community Associations develop classes and activities for relaxation during uncertain times.
    The YWCA's Bureau of Social Morality, formed in 1913, was a corps of women medical doctors trained to give sex education lectures. Concerned in particular about young women in the communities adjacent to army camps, the YWCA recruited and trained many more speakers who delivered over 2,000 lectures in 1917-18. During reconstruction, the YWCA enlarged the Bureau's mission to include lectures on general health topics, such as nutrition and hygiene, and rechristened it the Bureau of Social Education.
    The U.S. YWCA did similar work overseas during the war in Belgium, Czechoslovakia, France, Italy, the Near East, Poland, Romania, and Russia. War workers established centers "to help keep women fit for their work" by providing opportunities for rest, relaxation, and a good meal at a reasonable price. A special group of "Polish Gray Samaritans" served as nurses' aides for Polish soldiers fighting in France. Once the war was over the focus of the work shifted to reconstruction and aid for refugees. The "Polish Grays" concentrated their efforts in Poland.
    After the Armistice, the Continuation Committee (1919-22) and the Post-Continuation Committee (1921-22) kept much of the work begun by the War Work Council going using War Fund money.
    The rapid expansion of the War Work significantly changed the YWCA. It experienced what was described as fifteen years' growth in two. Many new Community Associations and Branches were formed and the existing emphasis of the work in many Associations changed, particularly in response to the influx of Industrial Club members. With the new members came increased expectations of "democratic control of Association policies and program." At the national level, the rapid increase put a huge emphasis on recruitment and training of staff, greatly increased the use of publications to "interpret" the Association, and dramatically broadened its program, both in size and scope. Sustaining such an organization proved impossible once the war was over.
    - War Work Council
      - General and History, 1918, 1932-39, n.d. (Box 702, Folder 1)
      - Minutes, May 1917-Oct 1919 (Box 702, Folder 2-6)
      - Executive Committee: minutes, May 1917-Oct 1919 (Box 702, Folder 7-15)
      - Commission to survey YWCA work in France, 1918 (Box 703, Folder 1)
      - Committees
        - Bureau of Social Education: leaflets series, circa 1919 (Box 703, Folder 2)
        - Colored Work
          - General, 1918-22, n.d. (Box 703, Folder 3)
          - Reports
            - General, 1917-20, n.d. (Box 703, Folder 4)
            - Josephine Pinyon, 1917-18, n.d. (Box 703, Folder 5)
          - The Work of Colored Women compiled by Jane Olcott, [1919] (Box 703, Folder 6)
        - Construction and Equipment: minutes, 1917-18 (Box 703, Folder 7)
        - Continuation and Post-Continuation: minutes, 1919-22 (Box 703, Folder 8-11)
        - Finance
          - Minutes, 1917-19 (Box 703, Folder 12-14)
          - Report: Financial Statement, 1918-19 (Box 703, Folder 15)
        - Hostess House
          - General, 1918-19, n.d. (Box 703, Folder 16-17)
          - Minutes
            - 1917 (Box 703, Folder 18)
            - 1918-20 (Box 704, Folder 1-6)
          - Report of the Hostess House Committee, 1919 (Box 704, Folder 7)
        - [Emergency] Housing
          - General by location, 1919-21 (Box 704, Folder 8)
          - Minutes
            - 1917-Jun 1921 (Box 704, Folder 9-15)
            - Jul-Dec 1921 (Box 705, Folder 1-2)
          - Report: "Suggestions for Housing Women War Workers made to the Secretary of War by the Housing Committee of the YWCA," Jan 1918 (Box 705, Folder 3)
        - Industrial
          - General, 1918-19, n.d. (Box 705, Folder 4-5)
          - Industrial War Service Centers/Clubs, 1918-23, n.d. (Box 705, Folder 6)
          - Publications
            - General (Box 705, Folder 7)
            - An Industrial Notebook, 1919 (Box 705, Folder 8-9)
          - Reports, 1917-20, n.d. (Box 706, Folder 1)
          - Research Section, 1919 (Box 706, Folder 2)
        - Junior War Work Council: minutes, 1917-18 (Box 706, Folder 3)
        - Land Service: minutes and reports, 1918 (Box 706, Folder 4)
        - Organization and Extension of Regular Work
          - Minutes, Nov 1917-20 (Box 706, Folder 5-10)
          - Reports by City/Town, 1919-21 (Box 706, Folder 11-14)
        - Overseas Committee and Overseas Subcommittee on Appointments
          - General: Emergency Services: A Statement of the Services Rendered by the Overseas Committee of the American YWCA in Ten Countries During and Following World War I, ca. 1940 (Box 707, Folder 1)
          - Minutes, Dec 1918-20 (Box 707, Folder 2-4)
          - Reports
            - Final report, 1917-20 (Box 707, Folder 5)
            - General, 1918-20 (Box 707, Folder 6)
            - Belgium, 1919 (Box 707, Folder 7)
            - Czecho-Slovakia, 1919-20 (Box 707, Folder 8-9)
            - France
              - General, 1917-20, n.d. (Box 707, Folder 10)
              - Reports
                - 1917-Apr 1919 (Box 707, Folder 11-17)
                - Jun 1919-1920, n.d. (Box 708, Folder 1-3)
              - "Summer Camps of the YWCA in France," 1919 (Box 708, Folder 4)
            - Italy, 1919-20 (Box 708, Folder 5)
            - Near East (Armenia, Turkey, Syria, Lebanon), 1919-20 (Box 708, Folder 6)
            - Poland, 1919-20 (Box 708, Folder 7)
            - Romania, 1919-20 (Box 708, Folder 8)
            - Russia
              - Miscellaneous, 1917-20 (Box 708, Folder 9-10)
              - Archangel, 1918-19 (Box 708, Folder 11)
              - Representative in Scandinavia, 1919-20 (Box 708, Folder 12)
              - Siberian Unit, 1919-20 (Box 708, Folder 13)
        - Pageantry and Drama, 1919 (Box 708, Folder 14)
        - Publicity Committee: broadsides, n.d. (Box 708, Folder 15)
        - Social Morality Committee
          - Minutes and reports, 1918-19, n.d. (Box 708, Folder 16)
          - [Final] Report, Jun 1917-Jul 1919 (Box 708, Folder 17)
          - Pamphlets and brochures, 1917-18, n.d. (Box 708, Folder 18)
        - Uniforms Committee, n.d. (Box 709, Folder 1)
        - Volunteer Workers Bureau
          - General, 1918, n.d. (Box 709, Folder 2)
          - Conference, Jun 1919 (Box 709, Folder 3)
          - Minutes and reports, Dec 1917-May 1919 (Box 709, Folder 4-7)
        - Work for Foreign-Born Women
          - General, 1918, n.d. (Box 709, Folder 8)
          - Minutes, 1917-20 (Box 709, Folder 9-10)
          - Reports
            - Summary, 1917, 1919-20 (Box 709, Folder 11)
            - Secretary
              - Miscellaneous, 1919 (Box 709, Folder 12)
              - Bird, Ethel, 1918-19 (Box 709, Folder 13)
              - Bradley, Ernestine C., 1919 (Box 709, Folder 14)
              - Bremer, Edith Terry, 1917-19 (Box 709, Folder 15)
              - Clark, Elizabeth W., 1919 (Box 709, Folder 16)
              - Crawford, Ruth, 1918 (Box 709, Folder 17)
              - Griel, Cecile, L., 1918-19 (Box 709, Folder 18)
              - Daykin, Anne B., 1918-19 (Box 709, Folder 19)
              - Hannah, Margaret, 1917-19 (Box 709, Folder 20)
              - Klotz, Justine, 1918-19 (Box 709, Folder 21)
              - Lowenstein, Alice Lili, 1919 (Box 709, Folder 22)
              - Rodakiewicz, Erla, 1919 (Box 709, Folder 23)
              - [Stanoyevich], Beatrice Stevenson, 1918-19 (Box 709, Folder 24)
              - Vaughn, Villa Curran (Mrs. T.H.), 1918-19 (Box 709, Folder 25)
              - Walkinshaw, Ruth, 1919 (Box 709, Folder 26)
          - Research and Information Section
            - "American Press Information," Jan-Jul 1919 (Box 709, Folder 27)
            - "Snap-shots of Some Folk With Whom We Neighbor" by Ruth Walkinshaw, 1918 (Box 709, Folder 28)
          - Polish Gray Samaritans Training School (aka Training School for Old Country Service)
            - General, 1918-19 (Box 709, Folder 29)
            - Minutes, 1918-19 (Box 709, Folder 30-31)
            - Reports, 1918-19, n.d. (Box 710, Folder 1-2)
            - Newspaper clippings, 1918-20 (Box 710, Folder 3)
            - Press releases, 1918-20 (Box 710, Folder 4)
            - Report, 1919 (Box 710, Folder 5)
            - Student evaluations and correspondence, 1919-33 (Box 710, Folder 6)
      - Conference, 6-7 Jun 1917 (Box 710, Folder 7-8)
      - Publications
        - General, 1917-19 (Box 710, Folder 9)
        - War Work Bulletin, Aug 1917-Sep 1919 (Box 710, Folder 10-17)
        - Blue Triangle News, Oct 1919-1920 (Box 710, Folder 18-19)
        - Y.W.C.A .Bulletin (published in France by YWCA of the USA), 1918-19 (Box 710, Folder 20)
      - Training Course, 6-15 Sep 1917
        - Anderson, Esther(?), "Our Work With Other Girls" (Box 711, Folder 1)
        - Baker, Oren C., "Travelers' Aid Society" (Box 711, Folder 2)
        - Bowles, Eva D., "The Colored Girl in This Country" (Box 711, Folder 3)
        - Bremer, Edith Terry, "Immigration and Foreign Community Work" and "Our Work Among Foreign Women" (Box 711, Folder 4)
        - Brown, Anna, "Our Social Morality Work" (Box 711, Folder 5)
        - Conde, Bertha "Personal Work with Girls" and "Our Work in Student Centers" (Box 711, Folder 6)
        - Cratty, Mabel, "The Genius of the Young Women's Christian Association" (Box 711, Folder 7)
        - Davis, Helen, "The National War Work Council" (Box 711, Folder 8)
        - Davis, Katharine (Box 711, Folder 9)
        - Gogin, Gertrude, "The National Service Commission" (Box 711, Folder 10)
        - Haynes, Rowland, "Recreation Work" (Box 711, Folder 11)
        - Holmquist, Louise, "The County Association" (Box 711, Folder 12)
        - Miner, Maude, "Probation Work" (Box 711, Folder 13)
        - Schaefer, Vera, "The Relationship of our Community Work with the Hostess House" (Box 711, Folder 14)
        - Simms, Florence, "The Girl in Industry" (Box 711, Folder 15)
        - Speer, (Mrs. Robert E.), "The Spiritual Significance Underlying Our Work" (Box 711, Folder 16)
        - Thomas, Helen, "Educational Work of the Association" (Box 711, Folder 17)
        - Williamson, Margaret, "Planning With Our Workers to Meet the Problem of Employment" (Box 711, Folder 18)
    - Organizations
      - Committee of Eleven, United War Work Campaign, Inc.
        - Articles of Incorporation and By laws, 1918 (Box 711, Folder 19)
        - Minutes, 1918-19, 1921 (Box 711, Folder 20-21)
      - General War-Time Commission of the Churches, Federal Council of Churches
        - General, n.d. (Box 711, Folder 22)
        - Minutes, 1917-19 (Box 711, Folder 23-26)
      - Industrial Commission [to Europe], spring 1919
        - General, 1919 (Box 711, Folder 27)
        - Background information, 1918-19, n.d. (Box 711, Folder 28)
        - Notes and drafts, 1919 (Box 711, Folder 29)
        - Report, 1919 (Box 711, Folder 30)
    - Publications, Womans Press
      - The Challenge of the Present Crisis by Harry Emerson Fosdick, 1917 (Box 712, Folder 1)
      - Madame France by R. Louise Fitch, 1919 (Box 712, Folder 2)
      - Mobilizing Woman Power by Harriot Stanton Blatch, 1918 (Box 712, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Hutchinson, Margaret: correspondence to family from United War Work Campaign in New Mexico, fall 1918 (Box 712, Folder 4)
      - James, Genevieve
        - Manuscript chapter re supervising Hostess Houses in southeastern U.S., n.d. (Box 712, Folder 5)
        - Scrapbook (disassembled 1988), 1917-19 (Box 712, Folder 6-10)
      - Ogden, Helen: typescript letters to family from Russia, 1917-18 (Box 712, Folder 11)
      - Sehon, Clarette (Box 713)
        - Biographical and general (Box 713, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence to family from France, Mar 1919-Jun 1920 (Box 713, Folder 2-10)
      - Tunnell, Winifred: miscellaneous memorabilia and clippings from work in France, 1918, n.d. (Box 713, Folder 11)
      - Miscellaneous memorabilia (Box 713, Folder 12)
    - OVERSIZE
      - Ellington Field (Texas) Hostess House scrapbook, 1917-18 (Box 714)
      - War Work Council, Committee on Work for Foreign-Born Women, Polish Gray Samaritan Training School (Box 715)
        - Logbook (Box 715, Folder 1)
        - Scrapbook (Box 715, Folder 2)
  - Subseries B. World War II
    - General and History (Box 715)
      - General, 1939-54, n.d. (Box 716, Folder 1-2)
      - Alien registration and legislation, 1940-45, n.d. (Box 716, Folder 3)
      - Bibliography "Origins of the European War," Oct 1939 (Box 716, Folder 4)
      - Conference: "The Role of Women in the War Effort," 24 Sep 1942 (Box 716)
        - General (Box 716, Folder 5)
        - Proceedings (Box 716, Folder 6-7)
      - Index to actions taken related to National Defense in the minutes of the National Board and Executive Committee, Jan 1937-Dec 1952 (Box 716, Folder 8)
      - Publications
        [see also USO in Subseries C. Defense Services]
        - General, 1942, n.d. (Box 716, Folder 9)
        - Program materials, 1942-45 (Box 716, Folder 10)
        - Women Behind the Lines: YWCA Program with War Production Workers, 1940-47 by Brooks Spivey Creedy, TWP, 1949 (Box 716, Folder 11)
      - Reconstruction
        - General, 1948, n.d. (Box 717, Folder 1)
        - Round-the-World YWCA Reconstruction Fund, 1946-48, n.d. (Box 717, Folder 2-5)
        - Study of Women's Dormitories, 1944 (Box 717, Folder 6)
    - Committees
      - Europe YWCA Emergency Committee (1940)/YWCA World Emergency Fund Committee (1941-42)/World Emergency and War Victims Fund Committee (1943-46)/World Emergency Fund Committee (1947-49)
        - Minutes, 1941-49 (Box 717, Folder 7-13)
        - Financial, 1943-45 (Box 717, Folder 14)
      - on Refugees
        - General, 1938-50 (Box 717, Folder 15-16)
        - Bulletin, 1938-39 (Box 717, Folder 17)
        - Minutes, 1941-45 (Box 717, Folder 18-21)
        - Publications, 1940-43 (Box 717, Folder 22)
        - Questionnaire to YWCA Industrial Club members, 1940-41 (Box 717, Folder 23)
        - Reference materials, 1938-41, n.d. (Box 717, Folder 24)
        - Reports
          - Refugees in the U.S., 1945 (Box 717, Folder 25)
          - Final Report, Committee on Refugees, circa 1945 (Box 717, Folder 26)
          - Secretary reports, 1938-40 (Box 717, Folder 27)
      - Postwar Reconstruction Leadership Counselling Group, 1942-43 (Box 718, Folder 1)
      - on Women Workers, 1942 (Box 718, Folder 2)
      - YWCA Volunteers in Civilian Defense, 1942-43 (Box 718, Folder 3)
    - American War-Community Services, Inc.
      - General, 1943-46, n.d. (Box 718, Folder 4-5)
      - Board of Directors, 1943-47 (Box 718, Folder 6-7)
      - Institute, Jan 1945 (Box 718, Folder 8)
      - YWCA
        - General, 1943-47 (Box 718, Folder 9)
        - War-Community Service Committee, 1943-46 (Box 718, Folder 10)
        - Staff meetings, 1943-44 (Box 718, Folder 11)
        - Reports
          - Annual, 1943-46 (Box 718, Folder 12-14)
          - Final, 1943-46 (Box 718, Folder 15)
          - Local, 1943-46
            - Arizona (Box 718, Folder 16)
            - California (Box 718, Folder 17-18)
            - Connecticut (Box 718, Folder 19)
            - Delaware (Box 718, Folder 20)
            - Georgia (Box 718, Folder 21)
            - Indiana (Box 719, Folder 1)
            - Kansas (Box 719, Folder 2)
            - Kentucky (Box 719, Folder 3)
            - Louisiana (Box 719, Folder 4)
            - Maryland (Box 719, Folder 5)
            - Michigan (Box 719, Folder 6)
            - Nebraska (Box 719, Folder 7)
            - New Jersey (Box 719, Folder 8)
            - New York (Box 719, Folder 9)
            - North Carolina (Box 719, Folder 10)
              [see also Kentucky]
            - Ohio (Box 719, Folder 11)
            - Oregon (Box 719, Folder 12)
            - YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 06. Program: Series VII. War Work and Defense Services, 1870-2002
              [Pennsylvania, see Ohio]
            - Tennessee (Box 719, Folder 13-14)
            - Texas (Box 719, Folder 15)
            - Virginia (Box 719, Folder 16)
            - West Virginia (Box 719, Folder 17)
          - Miscellaneous, 1942-44 (Box 719, Folder 18)
    - Japanese Evacuee Project
      - General
        - 1941-42 (Box 719, Folder 19-23)
        - 1943-46, n.d. (Box 720, Folder 1-5)
      - Clippings scrapbooks (photocopies), 1942-45
        - Scrapbooks 2 and 3: Denver, Colorado, press clippings (Box 720, Folder 6-7)
        - Scrapbook 4: metropolitan New York press (Box 720, Folder 8)
        - Scrapbook 5: California press (Box 720, Folder 9)
        - Scrapbook 6: magazine articles (Box 720, Folder 10)
      - Dissertation: "The Nisei in Denver, Colorado: A Study of Personality Adjustment and Disorganization" by Dorothy Kuniko Takechi, Fisk University, 1945 (Box 721, Folder 1)
      - Paper: "Behind Barbed Wire: The YWCA in the Japanese Internment Camps, 1942-46" by Rebecca Dobkins, UMass History 389, 1982 (Box 721, Folder 2)
      - Summary Report by Esther Briesemeister, 1942-46 (Box 721, Folder 3)
      - Committees (multi-organization in which YWCA participated)
        - Committee on Resettlement of Japanese Americans/Committee on Administration of Japanese Work, 1942-46 (Box 721, Folder 4-6)
        - Protestant Church Commission for Japanese Service, 1942-45 (Box 721, Folder 7-8)
        - YMCA-YWCA Coordinating Committee on Services to Persons of Japanese Ancestry, 1944-45 (Box 721, Folder 9)
      - Japanese American Citizens League, Special Emergency National Conference: minutes and supplement, Nov 1942 (Box 721, Folder 10-11)
      - Local Associations
        - Miscellaneous, 1943-44 (Box 721, Folder 12)
        - California
          - Miscellaneous, 1941-45 (Box 721, Folder 13)
          - Los Angeles, 1942-46 (Box 721, Folder 14-17)
        - Colorado: Denver, 1942-47 (Box 722, Folder 1-2)
        - Minnesota, 1944 (Box 722, Folder 3)
        - New Jersey, 1944 (Box 722, Folder 4)
        - Ohio, 1944 (Box 722, Folder 5)
        - Oregon, 1942 (Box 722, Folder 6)
        - Washington, 1942-46 (Box 722, Folder 7)
      - Student relocation, 1942-46 (Box 722, Folder 8)
      - U.S. Department of the Interior, War Relocation Authority, Japanese Relocation Centers
        - General
          - 1942-Oct 1943 (Box 722, Folder 9-10)
          - Nov 1943-46, n.d. (Box 722, Folder 11-13)
        - Abstracts, ca. 1942 (Box 722, Folder 14)
        - Community Analysis Notes, 1944-45 (Box 722, Folder 15)
        - Community Analysis Reports
          - 1943-44 (Box 722, Folder 16)
          - 1945-46 (Box 723, Folder 1)
        - Quarterly Reports, 1942 (Box 723, Folder 2)
        - YWCA Cooperation
          - General, 1942-46 (Box 723, Folder 3-4)
          - Arizona
            - Gila River (Rivers, AZ) (Box 723, Folder 5-7)
            - Poston (Poston, AZ) (Box 723, Folder 8-9)
          - Arkansas
            - Jerome (Denson, AR) (Box 723, Folder 10)
            - Rohwer (McGeehee, AR) (Box 723, Folder 11-12)
              [see also Jerome]
          - California
            - Manzanar (Manzanar, CA) (Box 723, Folder 13-17)
            - Tule Lake (Newell, CA) (Box 724, Folder 1-8)
          - Colorado: Granada (Amache, CO) (Box 724, Folder 9-14)
          - Idaho: Minidoka (Hunt, ID) (Box 724, Folder 15-17)
          - Texas: Crystal City (Crystal City, TX) (Box 724, Folder 18-19)
          - Utah: Central Utah (Topaz, UT) (Box 724, Folder 20-22)
          - Wyoming: Heart Mountain (Heart Mountain, WY) (Box 724, Folder 23-25)
    - OVERSIZE
      - Japanese Evacuee Project: clippings scrapbooks numbers 2-6, originals (Box 725)
        [DO NOT USE--use photocopies in box 720]
      - Duplicate photocopies of scrapbooks 2 and 3 (Box 725)
  - Subseries C. Defense Services
    - General and History
      - Miscellaneous, 1937, 1952 (Box 726, Folder 1)
      - "History of the Defense Services, National Board YWCA" by Mary Sims, 1950-57
        - Vol. I-II (Box 726, Folder 2-4)
        - Vol. III-V (Box 727, Folder 1-3)
      - "A Study of the Organized Junior Hostess Programs in the Defense Services Department of the YWCA and the Armed Services Department of the YMCA" by Mildred Luli Bair, 1956 George Williams College M.S. thesis (Box 728, Folder 1)
    - United Service Organizations (USO)
      - General and History
        - General, 1940-74, n.d. (Box 728, Folder 2-4)
        - Constitution and By-laws, 1941 (Box 728, Folder 5)
        - Anniversaries
          - 25th, 1965-66 (Box 728, Folder 6)
          - Guest book, 1966, 1971 (Box 728, Folder 7)
        - "Preliminary Material for the History of USO, Part II, Feb 10, 1941 to Pearl Harbor" by Julia M.H. Carson, 1945 (Box 729, Folder 1-3)
        - "USO in Skagway, Alaska, 1943-44" by Jane Hope Hastings, 1993 (Box 729, Folder 4)
      - Manual: "Community Conducted Operations," May 1943 (Box 729, Folder 5)
      - Reports, 1941-53, n.d. (Box 729, Folder 6)
      - YWCA Cooperation
        - General
          - 1940-59 (Box 729, Folder 7-11)
          - 1960-77, n.d. (Box 730, Folder 1-2)
        - Articles (unpublished) re USO by Genevieve James, 1941 (Box 730, Folder 3)
        - "History of the Participation of the YWCA in the USO [to June 1944]" by Emma P. Hirth (Box 730, Folder 4-15)
        - Commendation, 1945-46 (Box 730, Folder 16)
        - Conferences
          - War Production Workers, Nov 1944 (training conferences for YWCA staff in war production areas)
            - Notebook of records, 1944-45 (Box 731, Folder 1-6)
            - Reports from local associations collected for conference planning, 1944
              - Solicitation letter and summaries of reports (Box 731, Folder 7)
              - Reports from local associations, by state
                - A-Missouri (Box 731, Folder 8-11)
                - Nebraska-Z (Box 731, Folder 12-15)
        - Interracial: Negro World War II Workers, USO, 1941-45 (Box 731, Folder 16)
        - Local USO Clubs, 1951-62, n.d. (Box 731, Folder 17)
        - Publications
          - General pamphlets, 1951-53, n.d. (Box 732, Folder 1)
          - Democracy series pamphlets, 1943-45, n.d. (Box 732, Folder 2)
          - Counseling (Box 732, Folder 3)
          - Health and Recreation (Box 732, Folder 4)
          - Post-war (Box 732, Folder 5)
          - Program materials (Box 732, Folder 6-8)
          - Public Relations (Box 732, Folder 9)
          - Religion, 1943-53, n.d. (Box 732, Folder 10)
          - Teen Age, 1942-43, n.d. (Box 733, Folder 1)
          - Volunteers (Box 733, Folder 2)
          - Miscellaneous newsletters (Box 733, Folder 3)
          - Information Sheet, 1941-47 (Box 733, Folder 4-10)
          - Program Letters, n.d. (Box 733, Folder 11)
          - The Round-up
            - Bound copies
              - Sep 1951-Mar 1955 (Box 733, Folder 12-13)
              - Jan 1956-1959 (Box 734, Folder 1-2)
            - Unbound copies, 1952-61 (Box 734, Folder 3-12)
        - Reports
          - Compilation of Staff Reports on Rough Notes on Program Learnings in Constituency Groupings in the YWCA During the War Period, 1946 (Box 734, Folder 13)